Jabberwocky: the monster so horrible that people caught the plague to avoid it
Jabberwocky is a fantasy, comedy film directed by Terry Gilliam.
After the death of his father, young Dennis Cooper goes to
town where he has to pass several adventures.
The town and the whole kingdom is threatened by a
terrible monster called 'Jabberwocky'.
Will Dennis make his fortune?
Is anyone brave enough to defeat the monster?
Dennis Cooper, played by Michael Palin.
Squire, played by Harry H. Corbett.
Passelewe, played by John Le Mesurier.
Mr. Fishfinger, played by Warren Mitchell.
King Bruno the Questionable, played by Max Wall.
The Other Squire, played by Rodney Bewes.
Jabberwocky is a 1977 British fantasy comedy film
co-written and directed by Terry Gilliam.
Jabberwocky stars Michael Palin as Dennis, a cooper's apprentice, who is forced through clumsy,
often slapstick misfortunes to hunt a terrible dragon after the death of his father.
The film's title is taken from the nonsense poem "Jabberwocky" from
Lewis Carroll's Through the Looking-Glass (1871).
Gilliam's solo directorial debut, following co-directing Monty Python and the Holy Grail with
Terry Jones in 1975, the film received a mixed response from critics and audiences.
The film explores themes of new love, dreams, parent
child relationship, village, lewis carroll.
The tone is lighthearted.